RobertTan93@gmail.com

27 Hanna Avenue Richmond Hill, L4B 1Y9 Ontario, Canada

INTENT

Specializing in Finance

I am driven to solve complex financial problems because I find the solutions to be particularly rewarding, especially when presented to an audience that relies on quality results. I was first inspired by a professor leading a wealth management class while studying abroad in Singapore, working as a private banker on the side, he showed me that the world of finance is a challenging puzzle that is interconnected to form a complex mechanism. By working with my fellow peers in financial projects, I have learned not only that the work is fun and challenging but also some invaluable lessons about delegating, leadership, and creating an environment that maximizes creativity and produces quality solutions. I seek to continue the buy side path because it allows me to recommend solutions that have the ability to make a difference.

ATTRIBUTES - PROFESSIONAL

- · Project management and team leadership experience
- Experience managing a virtual team at remote locations
- Seek to influence and accommodate team to produce best results
- Put the team above myself, able to understand that people are key and must be prioritized
- Have technical skills (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, photography, Adobe CS, HTML, CSS) to get ahead of competition
- Use frameworks from great figures (ex. Dale Carnegie and Abraham Lincoln) in order to build great working relationships with people
- · Highly quantitative & analytical approach to thinking

ATTRIBUTES - PERSONAL

- . Highly adaptable, agile to constant change (location, type of work, colleagues)
- · Adventurous and risk taking by nature
- Eager to learn new material
- . Open minded to new ideas and ways of doing things

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Commerce, Queen's University, Kingston, ON **Fall Exchange**, Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

2015 2013

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Consultant, Queen's Business Consulting, Kingston, ON

2014-Present

Currently using market research and stakeholder analysis to tailor a business plan for Gananoque Police Services

Founder, Tan Photography

2012-Present

- Inspired by helping peers and opportunity to build relationships, identified and validated a need for well-executed corporate photographs and a lack of supply
- Faced financial obstacles obtaining necessary equipment, attained club grants and used equipment from Queen's Photo-Ops Studio
- Executed photographic services for individuals, expanded to committees, and conference teams in the Queen's School of Business, took market share from a dedicated Queen's School of Business PR photography team through word of mouth marketing

Managing Executive, Queen's Photo-Ops Studio, Kingston, ON

2011-Present

- Plan and execute photography workshops, provide personal guidance to inspire passion in new photographers
- · Workshops consistently fill at or over capacity, started hands on beginner lecture series to control market

RELEVANT EXTRACURRICULAR EXPERIENCE

Project Manager, Enactus Sustainability Consulting, Enactus Queen's

2013-Present

- Lead and develop virtual team of student analysts to develop and deliver research through online media
- Recommendations, built through detailed and holistic analysis, were presented to the Managing Director within the City of Kingston

- Recommendations were approved by the City of Kingston and an executive decision was made to move towards the implementation stage, where we are currently implementing a citywide marketing and revenue project
- Bill Rounding project 2013-Present: The objective was to assist a City of Kingston project called Sustainability Kingston (SK) which focused on making Kingston the most sustainable city in Canada, it needed to market itself and find financial streams to support its activities in the following year
- The main problem was the lack of connections of the project and financial constraints given by budget set by the City.
- The recommendation was to launch a bill rounding project involving Utilities Kingston as a sustainability partner to donate proceeds from rounding up bills towards SK and include informational material (linked to online material) within each mailed bill as a far reaching marketing tool
- Currently we are assisting SK in implementing the project by building a relationship with Utilities Kingston, taking them onboard as a client, and incepting the bill rounding idea from the inside
- I took engagement in all stages where team work was involved, organized and led meetings with both the client and the team, delegated the team throughout the research process which involved contacting 37 utility companies in the United States, gathering information for the deliverable, and graphical design and content of the final deliverable and presentation

Co-Founder/General Executive, Sparq Labs - Queen's Innovation Connector, Kingston, ON 2013-Present

- Co-founded the first campus-integrated Makerspace in Canada that aims to bring Queen's engineering to the cutting edge of education in a Silicon Valley-like environment
- Combined technical and sponsorship skills and led team to secure equipment and tools at cost from companies including Canadian Tire, and \$5,000 worth of CAD licenses from Solidworks
- Seeking revenue sourcing projects, and customer acquisition, achieved break even with team in under a year

Marketing Representative, Power Unit Youth Organization, Toronto, Ontario

2011-Present

- · Develop press releases, media kits, secure Markham councillors and mayor for press conference
- Lead the photography and filmography team for a three-day 130,000 patron-wide event
- Received Going Above & Beyond award for forward-thinking, improvement initiatives such as active assessment of sales processes and optimization of logistical activities

Co-Chair, Power Unit Youth Organization - Queen's Chapter, Kingston, ON

2012-Present

- Hired and currently delegating team of 15 towards raising a target of \$3,000 for Breast Cancer Action Kingston
- Personalized growth of individual executives through delegation and creation of value adding functions

Student Consultant, Marketing II, Queen's University

2012

- Prepared social media recruitment campaign for a PE firm with \$2.0 billion under management
- Recommendations influenced firm's use of recruitment channels for hiring Queen's School of Business undergraduates
- Recruitment of QSB Undergraduates project 2012: The objective was to assist a private equity firm to penetrate the QSB undergraduate talent and receive high calibre applications to fill its limited internship positions in the 2012-2013 term
- The main problem was the unfamiliarity of potential channels and inability to use them to full potential
- The recommended solution involved presenting the recommended marketing channels and explaining how to leverage their full potential, for example, one of the channels in the recommendations was Facebook and we detailed out what kind of content would best interest with QSB undergraduates in addition to introducing exclusive Facebook groups where the content could best penetrate the QSB population
- The firm received the recommendations and altered their original strategy which most importantly focused its weight on using Linkedln, which, through our analysis, was deemed to be a relatively ineffective tool to reach QSB undergraduates
- The latest update from the firm notified us that they successfully filled their positions with "high satisfaction" (2013)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Skills include: proficiency of Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Fireworks, InDesign, HTML, CSS, Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel), fluency in English, Polish and conversational in Mandarin

Interests include: investing & trading challenges (hosted by: Credit Suisse AG, Fortress IG, CIMB, placed 1/94 in first year trading project, and managing \$40,000 in parental funds), philanthropy, web design, fashion photography, tennis, and blues band performances (lead guitar)